Richard Eldridge

Website: https://richardeld.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Richardaeld | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-eldridge-4200221ab/

Software Developer

Software Developer with two years of daily coding experience. Equally comfortable in front-end or back-end development. Object-Oriented Program (OOP) language specialization is JavaScript with additional skills in Python, Django, React.js, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, and more. Excellent written and verbal communication skills, experience working in a collaborative team environment, and strong troubleshooting skills gained from multiple hackathons and previous employment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

| Technologies | Databases | Frameworks | Libraries | Version | Other |
|--|---|---|--|----------------------------|---|
| PythonJavaScriptHTML5CSS3 | MongoDBPostgreSQLSQLite | DjangoFlaskExpress.js | BootstrapReact.jsKnex.js | Control Git GitHub | Node.jsHerokuAmazon Web Service (AWS)Object-Oriented Programming |
| | | | | | Google Searches |

EDUCATION AND TRAINING:

May 2020 - Nov. 2021 Code Institute - Software Development Diploma *EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

PERN project with RESTful API: DM Tool (front-end) | Repository (front-end) | Repository (API)

May 2022

A full-stack PERN project that allows users to view a plethora of DND content and allows authorized admins to control content. Technology used: PERN (PostgreSQL, Express.js, React, Node.js), Knex.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Github, Heroku, VSCode

E-commerce Bookstore: Eldridge Music Book Emporium | Repository

Nov. 2021

A full-stack e-commerce bookstore application designed for users to search, rate, and purchase music books.

Technology used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, Stripe, VSCode

Recipe Compendium: Fat Raccoon | Repository

Jun. 2021

A full-stack recipe app with a colorful and intuitive UX that allows users to upload, view, edit, and share recipes.

Technology used: Python, Flask, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku

HACKATHON PROJECTS:

Smitten: Smitten | Repository

Feb. 2022

A front-end Valentine's Day themed game designed to entertain fans of the popular application Wordle.

This project achieved 1st place in Code Institute's, "Love is in the Air" February 2022 Hackathon event.

My Contributions: JavaScript, CSS | My Role: Scrum Master, Lead JavaScript Debugger

Wheelchair Accessibility Calculator App: Spinning Wheelchairs | Repository

Sept. 2021

A front-end project designed to determine if a hallway or doorway has adequate space for a wheelchair's turn radius.

This project achieved 3rd place in Code Institute's Trust in SODA 2021 Hackathon event.

My Contributions: JavaScript, HTML, CSS | My role: JavaScript Algebra Implementer

WORK EXPERIENCE:

SGPS ShowRig, Inc., Norcross, GA

Feb. 2015 - Jun. 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control | Nov. 2019 – Jun. 2020

- Repaired and serviced motors and filed detailed tickets in a P.O.S. system. Delegated responsibilities. Power and Control Technician | Feb. 2018 – Nov. 2019
- Repaired and serviced electrical equipment and filed detailed tickets in a P.O.S. system. Department Head of Rigging | Feb. 2015 – Feb. 2018

Learned two different P.O.S. systems and trained others. Delegated responsibilities.